纽约市
翻译　Wanderlust　Renoad
字　　幕　　侠
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
翻译　舒九　我的后面是猪精
ZIMUXIA.CN
校对　蘑人啾啾　宇宙的大柚子　时间轴　iiichiii
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
后期　Jason肖　特效　小布
我这就去协调搜救
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
监制　蘑人啾啾　宇宙的大柚子
我这就去协调搜救
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
ZIMUXIA.CN
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
讲道理 你们怎么受得了他
I mean, honestly, how do you keep your food down?
闭嘴
Shut up.
大块头
Buddy!
你怎么想的 电梯满员了
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
走楼梯去
Take the stairs.
就是 别进来
Yeah. Stop, stop.
箱子拿来 斯塔克
Hand over the case, Stark.
交出来
Hand it over.
-斯塔克  -斯塔克
- Stark? - Stark?
深呼吸 深呼吸
Breathe, breathe.
干得好 在巷子里等我 我吃块披萨就走
Good job. Meet me in the alley. I'm gonna grab a quick slice.
不要走楼梯
No stairs!
洛基呢
Where's Loki?
洛基 洛基
Loki! Loki!
蒙古戈壁滩
我是来自阿斯加德的洛基
I am Loki of Asgard.
我背负着光荣的使命
And I am burdened with glorious purpose.
你是谁?
为什么来我们家?
我...
I...
算了
Never mind.
别碰它
Don't touch that.
看来是标准的时序违规
Appears to be a standard sequence violation.
此时间分支正以稳定的速率和斜率增长
Branch is growing at a stable rate and slope.
时间犯已确认
Variant identified.
你说什么
I beg your pardon.
我代表时间变异管理局
On behalf of the Time Variance Authority,
以触犯神圣时间线的罪名逮捕你
I hereby arrest you for crimes against the Sacred Timeline.
举起手来
Hands up.
跟我们走
You're coming with us.
不好意思 "我们"是谁
I'm sorry. Who's "us"?
最后一次机会 时间犯
Last chance, Variant.
我今天很累了
It's been a very long day,
也受够了听全副武装的傻子对我唠叨
and I think I've had my fill of idiots in armored suits telling me what to do,
所以不好意思 这是你的最后一次机会
so, if you don't mind, this is actually your last chance.
不要挡我的路
Now get out of my way.
现在你的行动速度降到了1/16
You are now moving at 1/16th speed,
但感知的疼痛是实时的
but feeling all that pain in real time.
重置时间线
Reset the timeline.
-什么种族  -斯克鲁时间犯
- What species? - Variant Skrull.
这什么地方
What is this place?
我爸是高盛的董事会成员
My dad is on the board of Goldman Sachs.
[一家国际领先的投资银行]
他打个电话 你的工作立马就要丢
One more call and your whole job is privatized.
-好了  -你的破工作 怎么样
- All right. - Your little job. How'd you like that?
你好 先生
Hello, sir.
-跟我来  -你这是犯了大错
- Come on. - You're making a terrible mistake.
严重的错
You're making a big mistake.
-你好 长官...  -把它列为证据
- Hello, ma'am... - Log this as evidence.
起码告诉我这是什么吧
Can you at least tell me what it is?
是宇宙魔方 你给我小心点
It's the Tesseract. Be very careful with it.
听着真傻
It sounds dumb.
你记住
Know this.
惹恼了我 后果很致命
You cross me, there are deadly consequences.
走着瞧吧
We'll see.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
这可是上等阿斯加德皮革
This is fine Asgardian leather.
站稳别动
Hold very still.
你稍等一下
Now, hang on just a minute.
请签字确认这是你的毕生语录
Please sign to verify this is everything you've ever said.
什么
What?
这个也要签
Sign this, too.
什么?
太荒唐了吧
Oh, this is absurd.
还有这个
And this.
请确认 据你所知 自己不是机器人
Please confirm to your knowledge that you are not a fully robotic being,
而是有机生物
were born an organic creature,
拥有许多文化里称之为"灵魂"的东西
and do in fact possess what many cultures would call a soul.
什么 "据我所知"
What? "To my knowledge"?
很多人不知道自己是不是机器人吗
Do a lot of people not know if they're robots?
感谢您的确认 请过安检门
Thank you for confirming. Please move through.
万一我是机器人 可我不知道呢
What if I was a robot and I didn't know it?
那机器就会把你彻底熔化
The machine would melt you from the inside out.
请过安检门 先生
Please move along, sir.
好吧 我不是机器人 不会有事的
Okay, I'm not a robot, so I'll be fine.
怎么回事
What?
-那是什么  -你的现世光环
- Oh, what's that? - Your temporal aura.
-什么东西  -请进门
- What's that? - Please, through the door.
请取票
Take a ticket.
这是熟食店吗 我不取
What is this, a deli? No.
请取票
Take a ticket.
这里只有我们两个人
There's only two of us in here.
请取票
Take a ticket.
肯定搞错了 我不该在这里
This is a mistake! I shouldn't be here!
你好呀 你可能在说
Hey there! You're probably saying,
"肯定搞错了 我不该在这里"
"This is a mistake. I shouldn't even be here."
欢迎来到时间变异管理局
Welcome to the Time Variance Authority.
我是时间小姐
I'm Miss Minutes,
我的职责是 在你受审前 为你讲清来龙去脉
and it's my job to catch you up before you stand trial for your crimes.
所以就不浪费时间啦
So let's not waste another minute.
请坐稳 准备好 认真听讲吧
Settle in, sharpen your pencils, and check this out.
很久以前 爆发了一场大规模多元宇宙战争
Long ago, there was a vast multiversal war.
无数条时间线为争夺霸权而彼此争斗
Countless unique timelines battled each other for supremacy,
最终几乎彻底毁灭了
nearly resulting in the total destruction of
世间万物
well, everything.
后来 无所不知的时间守护者出现了
But then, the all-knowing Time-Keepers emerged,
将多元宇宙重组为单一时间线 从而带来了和平
bringing peace by reorganizing the multiverse into a single timeline,
这就是神圣时间线
the Sacred Timeline.
现在 时间守护者守护并保持着正确的时间流动
Now, the Time-Keepers protect and preserve the proper flow of time
监管万事万物
for everyone and everything.
但有时 像你这样的人会偏离时间守护者创造的轨道
But sometimes, people like you veer off the path the Time-Keepers created.
这就是时间犯
We call those Variants.
也许你引发了暴动 或者只是上班迟到了
Maybe you started an uprising, or were just late for work.
总之 偏离时间轨道会导致联结事件
Whatever it was, stepping off your path created a nexus event,
联结
若不加以控制 就可能会疯狂产生分支
which, left unchecked, could branch off into madness,
联结
再次引发多元宇宙战争
leading to another multiversal war.
危险: 多元宇宙
但是 别担心
But, don't worry,
为避免这种情况
to make sure that doesn't happen,
时间守护者创立了时变局 和它了不起的员工
the Time-Keepers created the TVA and all its incredible workers.
时变局介入 纠正你的错误
The TVA has stepped in to fix your mistake
让时间重回预定的轨道
and set time back on its predetermined path.
你的行为导致你在时间线上没有了立足之处
Now that your actions have left you without a place on the timeline,
你就必须为自己的罪行接受审判
you must stand trial for your offenses.
请耐心等待 你很快就会见到法官
So sit tight, and we'll get you in front of a judge in no time.
请拿好票
Just make sure you have your ticket,
下一位有空的助理会接待你
and you'll be seen by the next available attendant.
-永永远远  -始终如此
- For all time. - Always.
时间守护者 神圣时间线
Time-Keepers? The Sacred Timeline?
谁信这种胡话啊
Who actually believes this bunkum?
-请出示票 先生  -他没给我 我找他要了
- Ticket, sir? - He didn't give me a ticket. I tried to ask for one.
-请出示票 先生  -我找那人要过了
- Ticket, sir! - I tried to ask that guy for a ticket!
先生...
Sir...
怎么 你还想吼我 你个白痴
What, you're raising your voice at me, bucket head?
感谢您到访时变局
Thanks for visiting the TVA.
欢迎您对我们的工作进行评价
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.
第一季 第 1 集
法国 艾克斯
追捕者与时间卫士来解决一起常规联结事件
The hunter and his Minutemen responded to a routine nexus event.
他们到达时 似乎遭遇了突袭
It appears that when they arrived, somebody got the jump on 'em.
你怎么看
You think?
是他
It's him.
刀伤看起来与其受害人一致
Yeah, stab wounds look consistent with the others.
尸体的倒地姿势表明他们对袭击者毫不知情
Positioning of the bodies indicates they didn't know what the hell hit 'em.
重置器也没了
And reset charge is gone.
这是上周的第六次袭击了
That's the sixth attack in the last week.
还有不知道的呢
That we know of.
等等 慢着 别开火
Wait, stand down! Stand down.
只是个孩子
It's just a kid.
抱歉...
...我朋友有点笨
我也会说这条时间线上的所有语言
傻子
点一下
Tap it.
你知道是谁做的吗?
别担心 恶魔也怕我们
Don't worry, that devil's afraid of us.
我们会解决掉他的
We're gonna take care of him.
也会把你送回你该去的地方
And we're gonna put you back where you belong.
蓝色的...
那是什么?
恶魔带来的礼物
Devil bearing gifts.
去查查 看有没有序列周期或现世光环的线索
Go ahead and run this for sequence period and any hints of temporal aura.
肯定查不出什么结果的
You know we won't get anything.
试试看吧
Yeah, just give it a shot.
时间分支接近红线了 我们得走了
The branch is nearing red line. We need to go.
好
Okay.
去外面等吧
没事的
It's okay.
设置重置器
Set a reset charge.
长官 有东西请您过目
Sir, there's something you'll wanna see.
__________
时间犯姓名
洛基·劳菲森
种族
冰霜巨人
身高
1.88m
眼睛颜色
蓝色
性别
流动
出生地
约顿海姆
别名
洛基·奥丁森 诡计之神
已逮捕
下一位
Next case, please.
劳菲森 时间犯L1130 即洛基·劳菲森
Laufeyson. Variant L1130, AKA Loki Laufeyson,
被指控违反时间序列7-20-89
is charged with sequence violation 7-20-89.
你对此作何辩护
How do you plead?
女士 神从不辩护
Madam, a god doesn't plead.
这出闹剧很有趣 不过我现在想回家了
This has been a very enjoyable pantomime, but I'd like to go home now.
你是否有罪 先生
Are you guilty or not guilty, sir?
罪在作为诡计之神吗 我有罪
Guilty of being the God of Mischief? Yes.
罪在认为这一切乏味至极吗 我有罪
Guilty of finding all this incredibly tedious? Yes.
罪在违反了神圣时间线吗
Guilty of a crime against the Sacred Timeline?
那绝对不是 你们抓错人了
Absolutely not, you have the wrong person.
是吗 那我们该抓谁
Oh, really? And who should we have?
我猜是 复仇者联盟
I suspect, the Avengers.
我能拿到宇宙魔方 是因为他们穿越时间
I came into possession of the Tesseract because they traveled through time,
这无疑是他们阻挠我成为众神之王的最后一搏
no doubt in a last-ditch effort to stave off my ascent to God King.
你这指控可不轻啊
That's quite an accusation.
相信我 能闻到两个托尼·斯塔克的古龙水味
Believe me, you can smell the cologne of two Tony Starks.
既然要抓时间罪犯 就应该抓他们
You speak of Time Criminals? It's they you should be after.
或者你给我一支特遣队和一些资源
Perhaps you could provide me with a taskforce and resources,
让我回去替你消灭他们
and I could return and eliminate them for you.
我们要讨论的不是复仇者
We're not here to talk about the Avengers.
-不是吗  -不是
- Oh, no? - No.
他们的所作所为是应该的 但你不该逃跑
What they did was supposed to happen. You escaping was not.
好吧
Right.
"不该发生" 谁规定的
"Not supposed to happen"? According to whom?
时间守护者
The Time-Keepers?
时间守护者 对
The Time-Keepers. Right.
让我跟时间守护者 来场神与神的谈话吧
Well, perhaps I should speak to these Time-Keepers, gods to gods.
抱歉 他们很忙的
I'm sorry, but they're quite busy.
是吗 他们忙什么
They are? What are they doing?
控制时间正确流动
Dictating the proper flow of time.
这样啊 那你是做什么的
I see. Right. And then what do you do?
根据他们的指示 控制时间正确流动
Dictate the proper flow of time according to their dictations.
你作何辩护
How do you plead?
我的罪
Guilty
就是这个
of this.
-怎么回事  -慢着 你们别吵
- What's going on? - Hang on. Everyone quiet.
-他想用他的能力 法官  -别催我
- He's trying to use his powers, ma'am. - Don't rush me.
该死 为什么不管用
Damn it! Why won't it work?
魔法吗
Magic powers?
在时变局可不好用 劳菲森先生
They're no good in the TVA, Mr. Laufeyson.
法庭认为你有罪 我宣判将你重置
The court finds you guilty, and I sentence you to be reset.
下一位
Next case, please!
"重置" 什么意思
"Reset"? What does that mean?
很可怕吗 什么意思
What, is it bad? What does it mean?
你们这些可笑的官僚 才不能控制我的故事结局
You ridiculous bureaucrats will not dictate how my story ends!
这不是你的故事 劳菲森先生 从来都不是
It's not your story, Mr. Laufeyson. It never was.
你们不知道我的本事
You have no idea what I'm capable of!
我... 我应该知道
I... I think I might.
知道他的本事
Have an idea of what he's capable of.
近法官席来
Approach the bench.
如果你想的是那件事 那不是什么好主意
If you're thinking what I think you are thinking, it's a bad idea.
我只是跟着直觉走
Okay, I'm just chasing a hunch.
出了任何差错 责任你来背
Anything goes sideways, it's on you.
好 我感觉总是在仰望你
Okay. I feel like I'm always looking up to you.
我喜欢 很合适
I like it. It's appropriate.
你又是谁
And who are you?
我要把这个地方烧为灰烬
I'm gonna burn this place to the ground.
我带你去我办公室 你可以从那儿开始
I'll show you where my desk is, you can start there.
看看吧
Have a look.
美好家园
Home sweet home.
这儿不是没有魔法吗
I thought there was no magic here.
确实没有
There isn't.
这不是真的
That's not real.
是真的 不幸的是 所有文书工作也是真的
It is, and, unfortunately, so is all the paperwork.
不过很适合给你放火 走吧
Good tinder for your fire, though. Come on.
这里真是个梦魇
This place is a nightmare.
那是另一个部门
That's another department.
那个部门 我愿意帮你一起烧
Now that department I'll help you burn down.
对了 我是莫比乌斯探员
I'm Agent Mobius, by the way.
这是要带我去刑场吗
Are you taking me somewhere to kill me?
不 刚才那里才是刑场
No. That's where you just were.
我要带你找个地方谈谈
I'm taking you some place to talk.
我不喜欢说话
I don't like to talk.
但你喜欢说谎 上一句就是
But you do like to lie, which you just did.
你我都知道 你很爱说话
Because we both know you love to talk.
小嘴不停
Talkie-talkie.
你在这儿多久了
How long have you been here?
不知道 很难讲 时变局的时间流动方式不同
I don't know. It's hard to say, time passes differently here in the TVA.
-什么意思  -你马上就明白了
- What does that mean? - You'll catch up.
所以你也是时变局勇敢敬业的员工吗
So, you're part of the TVA's courageous and dedicated workforce?
没错
Yes.
-时间守护者创造了你  -对
- You were created by the Time-Keepers. - Yep.
-保护神圣时间线  -正确
- To protect the Sacred Timeline. - Correct.
好笑吗
Is that funny?
这么个小地方 决定了数万亿人的生命
The idea that your little club decides the fate of trillions of people
一切存在都听命于三只太空蜥蜴
across all of existence at the behest of three space lizards,
确实很好笑
yes, it's funny.
很荒唐
It's absurd.
你不是不爱说话吗
I thought you didn't like to talk.
你先请
After you.
说实话 这里感觉真的很像个刑场
For the record, this really does feel like a killing-me kind of a room.
你很不信任别人啊
Not big on trust, are you?
小孩和狗才轻信他人
Trust is for children and dogs.
只有一个人可以信任
There's only one person you can trust.
你自己吗 我喜欢
Yourself? I like it.
我要印在T恤上
Slap it on a T-shirt.
如果时变局真的管控所有时间
If the TVA truly oversees all of time,
我此前为何从未听说过
how have I never heard of you until now?
因为你不必知道
'Cause you've never needed to.
你一直活在设定好的时间轨道里
You've always lived within your set path.
我的人生轨道都是我自己的选择
I live within whatever path I choose.
是是是 好了 过来坐
Sure you do. Okay, come have a seat.
跟你说了 时变局里的时间流动方式不同
I told you, time moves differently in the TVA.
过来 坐下
Come on, sit down.
我们开始吧
Let's get into this.
过来坐
Go on, have a seat.
你的眼神能杀人
If looks could kill.
你想要我做什么
What do you want from me?
首先 需要你小小的配合
Well, let's start with a little cooperation.
我不擅长
Not my forte.
是吗
Really?
即使是讨好你准备背叛的大人物也不行吗
Even when you're wooing someone powerful you intend to betray?
行了
Come on.
你一点都不了解我
You don't know anything about me.
那我愿意了解了解
Maybe I'd like to learn.
我专门负责追捕危险的时间犯
I specialize in the pursuit of dangerous Variants.
像我这种吗
Like myself?
不 我是说极其危险的时间犯
No, particularly dangerous Variants.
你顶多是只小猫咪
You're just a little pussycat.
我有问题问你
I got a set of questions for you.
你要是诚实作答
You answer them honestly,
我可以给你 你想要的东西
and then maybe I can give you something you want.
你想离开这里 对吧
You wanna get out of here, right?
那就从这里开始
Yeah, so we'll start there.
要是回去了 你会做什么
Should you return, what are you gonna do?
-完成我未竟的事业  -是什么
- Finish what I started. - Which is?
夺得王位
Claim my throne.
你想当王吗
You wanna be king?
不是想当 我生来就是
I don't want to be, I was born to be.
行 那到底是什么的王呢
I know, but king of what exactly?
你不会懂的
You wouldn't understand.
说来听听
Try me.
米德加德
Midgard.
也就是地球
AKA Earth.
好吧 当上米德加德之王以后呢
All right. Now you're the king of Midgard, then what?
幸福快乐的生活
Happily ever after?
阿斯加德 九大国度
Asgard, the Nine Realms.
-太空  -太空
- Space? - Space?
太空很大的 也够你炫耀了
Space is big. That'd be a nice feather in your cap.
"洛基 太空之王"
"Loki, the King of Space."
你敢嘲笑我
Mock me if you dare.
不 我可没有
No, I'm not.
说实话 我算是个粉丝
Honestly, I'm actually a fan. Yeah.
我其实很好奇
And I guess I'm wondering
为什么你明明这么强大 却只想统治别人呢
why does someone with so much range just wanna rule?
我可以让他们轻松点
I would've made it easy for them.
谁都喜欢轻松
People like easy.
最早且最沉重的谎言
The first and most oppressive lie ever uttered
就是歌颂自由
was the song of freedom.
这话怎么说
How's that one go?
对于几乎所有生命体
For nearly every living thing,
选择会带来羞愧 疑惑和悔恨
choice breeds shame and uncertainty and regret.
每条路都有分岔
There's a fork in every road,
总有人选错
yet the wrong path always taken.
的确
Good. Yeah.
你说 "几乎所有生命体"
You said "nearly every living thing,"
你应该不属于这个范畴吧
so I'm guessing you don't fall into that category?
时间守护者的马戏团挺大
The Time-Keepers have built quite the circus,
各位小丑也都各司其职 完美演出
and I see the clowns are playing their parts to perfection.
你真爱用比喻 我喜欢
Big metaphor guy. I love it.
显得你超级聪明
Makes you sound super smart.
我本来就聪明
I am smart.
我知道
I know.
好
Okay.
这是什么
What is this?
你生命重要时刻的采样结果 来
A sampling of your greatest hits, if I may.
你们不介意的话...
If it's all the same to you...
现在可以喝了
I'll have that drink now.
不用了
No.
我记得 我在场
And I remember. I was there.
还有别的吗
Anything else?
很有意思 你生来就该统治 可你总是失败
It's funny, for someone born to rule, you sure do lose a lot.
甚至可以说是刻在你骨子里的
You might even say it's in your nature.
上一个这么跟我说的人
You know, things didn't turn out so well
下场可不太好
for the last person who said that to me.
是 菲尔·寇森
Oh, yeah, Phil Coulson.
不
No!
复仇者联盟聚集起来 不就是想打败你 为他复仇吗
Didn't the Avengers come together to literally avenge him by defeating you?
慰藉死者罢了
Little solace to a dead man.
你是不是喜欢伤害别人
Do you enjoy hurting people?
让他们觉得自己弱小
Making them feel small?
觉得害怕
Making them feel afraid?
-你的把戏吓不到我  -觉得渺小
- Your games don't frighten me. - Making them feel little?
我知道自己是谁
I know what I am.
-凶手吗  -解放者
- A murderer? - A liberator.
可能是解放眼球吧
Of eyeballs, maybe.
看看你的微笑 你就是喜欢
Look at that smile. You are enjoying that.
你喜欢伤害别人吗
Did you enjoy hurting them?
我不用玩这种游戏 我可是神
I don't have to play this game. I'm a god.
什么来着 诡计之神对吧
Of what, again? Mischief, right?
我看不出这里面有什么诡计啊
Yeah. I don't see anything very mischievous about this.
你确实看不出来
No, I don't suppose you do.
谈谈你逃跑的事吧
Let's talk about your escapes.
你真的很擅长做尽坏事 然后逃跑
You're really good at doing awful things, and then just getting away.
我能说什么 我是诡计多端的骗子
What can I say? I'm a mischievous scamp.
这段我最喜欢
This is one of my favorites.
我是本次机长 威廉·A·斯科特
From the flight deck, Captain William A. Scott,
西北航空305号航班 将准时降落西雅图
Northwest Orient Airlines 305, on schedule to land in Seattle.
今日飞行时间 大约为...
Flight time today, approximately...
波旁酒加汽水吗
Bourbon and soda?
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气 还需要什么其他的吗 先生
Absolutely. Is there anything else I can do for you, sir?
你看看就知道了
I suppose we'll find out, won't we?
-小姐  -怎么了 库珀先生
- Uh, Miss? - Yes, Mr. Cooper?
你先看看纸条吧
You might want to take a look at that note.
我带了炸弹
I have a bomb.
我看不出这段的重点在哪里...
I fail to see how this has any relevance or bearing on...
别急 精彩的要来了
No. This is the good part.
回头见
See you again someday.
哥 海姆达尔 你们给我准备好
Brother, Heimdall, you better be ready.
不敢相信你就是D.B.库珀 天哪
I can't believe you were D.B. Cooper. Come on!
[世上首位劫机成功的劫犯 劫机后顺利逃脱 劫机案至今未破]
我当时还年轻 打赌输给索尔了
I was young, and I lost a bet to Thor.
我掺和这些事的时候 时变局在哪儿呢
Where was the TVA when I was meddling with these affairs of men?
我们也在 都是顺着神圣时间线的
We were right there with you, just surfing that Sacred Timeline.
时间守护者允许发生这种事 是吗
So that had the Time-Keepers' seal of approval, did it?
这不是允许不允许的问题
Well, I wouldn't think of it in terms of approval and disapproval.
更像是...
That's sort of a...
继续说逃跑
Let's get back to escapes,
还有心理学套话吧
and a little psychobabble.
你觉得你到底在逃避什么
What is it that you think that you're really running from?
够了
Enough.
回来坐好
Back in your cage.
我也能治得了你
See, I can play the heavy keys, too.
我站起来 是想表达一下立场
I was just standing up to make a point.
抱歉 你继续
I'm sorry, go ahead.
现在再站起来没意思了
It won't be as meaningful now.
那行 坐着吧
Okay, well, stay seated.
我想怎样就怎样
I'll do what I want to do!
没问题
Sure.
你到底想要什么
What exactly is it that you want?
我想要你诚实面对自己行为的动机
I want you to be honest about why you do what you do.
骗子
Liar.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我只是想要深入了解 令人畏惧的诡计之神
All I seek is a deeper understanding of the fearsome God of Mischief.
是什么驱使着洛基
What makes Loki tick?
-我知道这儿是什么了  -是什么
- I know what this place is. - What is it?
是个幻觉
It's an illusion.
是弱者残忍又精巧的手段 想让人害怕罢了
It's a cruel, elaborate trick conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
绝望地想要掌控全局
A desperate attempt at control.
你们大摇大摆
Now, you all parade about
好像自己是宇宙神圣的仲裁人
as if you're the divine arbiters of power in the universe.
-我们的确是  -才不是
- We are. - You're not.
我的选择是我自己的
My choices are my own.
你的选择是你自己的 好 我们继续
Your choice is your own. Good, let's go with that.
看了这个 你肯定很兴奋
I think this one's gonna fire you up.
自由的诱惑 吞噬了生命中的快乐
The bright lure of freedom diminishes your life's joy
你们疯狂争权夺势...
in a mad scramble for power...
没错
Precisely.
我当时...
I was...
我马上就要拿回属于我的东西了
I am on the verge of acquiring everything I am owed,
到那时 也只是因为我做到了
and when I do, it'll be because I did it.
不是因为应该如此
Not because it was supposed to happen.
不是因为你 或者时间变异管理局
Or because you or the Time Variance Authority,
随便你们自称什么东西 允许我这么做
or whatever it is you call yourselves, allowed me to.
说实话 你真可悲
Honestly, you're pathetic.
你根本无关紧要
You're an irrelevance.
是我绕了点路
A detour.
是我登顶的垫脚石
A footnote to my ascent.
说完了吗
You finished?
你得认真一点了
You're gonna start taking things seriously.
如果你没捡起宇宙魔方
If you hadn't picked up the Tesseract,
就会被送回阿斯加德的牢房
you would have been taken to a cell on Asgard.
洛基
Loki.
你好 母亲
Hello, Mother.
你为我骄傲吗
Have I made you proud?
别火上浇油了
Please don't make this worse.
这是什么东西
What is this?
都是骗局 把戏 根本没这种事
This is nonsense, more tricks. This never even happened.
你没遇到
Not to you.
暂时而已
Not yet.
时变局不止知道你的过去
Look, the TVA doesn't just know your whole past,
还有你的一生 你注定的命运
we know your whole life, how it's all meant to be.
把这当作一种安慰
Think of it as comforting.
太荒唐了
This is absurd.
难道我不是你母亲吗
And am I not your mother?
你不是
You're not.
你总能把所有人看透 除了你自己
Always so perceptive about everyone but yourself.
然后黑暗精灵袭击了宫殿
And then the Dark Elves attack the palace,
你以为你把他们引到了索尔那里
and you think you send them to Thor.
走左边的楼梯
You might wanna take the stairs to the left.
但实际上 你把他们引到了...
But instead, you send them...
我不会说的
I'll never tell.
你把她藏到哪儿了 她在哪儿
Where do you have her? Where is she?
你把他们引去找她了
You lead them right to her.
我不信 你骗人 这不是真的
I don't believe you. You're lying. It's not true.
是真的
It is true.
这才是正确的时间线
That's the proper flow of time,
这件事会一遍又一遍地发生 因为它本该如此
and it happens again and again and again because it's supposed to,
也必须如此
because it has to.
-时变局会确保这一点  -她在哪儿
- The TVA makes sure of it. - Where is she?
请你告诉我 你喜欢伤害别人吗
Now why don't you tell me, do you enjoy hurting people?
-我不相信  -你喜欢杀戮吗
- I don't believe you. - Do you enjoy killing?
-我要杀了你  -就像对你母亲一样吗
- I'll kill you. - What, like you did your mother?
抱歉 时间逆转器只对你有效 家具不会受影响
Sorry, the Time Twister just loops you, not the furniture.
你并非生而为王 洛基
You weren't born to be king, Loki.
而是造成痛苦 折磨和死亡
You were born to cause pain and suffering and death.
现在如此 过去如此 将来如此
That's how it is, that's how it was, that's how it will be.
也让别人成就最辉煌的自我
All so that others can achieve their best versions of themselves.
这到底是什么鬼地方
What is this place?
起来吧
Come on.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
工作 你的工作就是打断别人吗
My job. Is it yours to interrupt?
有情况了
We have a situation.
我们总有情况
There's always a situation.
哪儿都别去
Don't go anywhere.
越来越有状态了
It was just getting good. Spirited.
-你不该和那个时间犯谈  -那是你的立场
- Talking to that Variant is a mistake. - That's your position.
-我的立场恰恰相反...  -他该被重置
- I think the opposite... - He should be reset!
你觉得谁都该被重置 我有有用的信息
You think everyone should be reset. I'm getting good stuff!
又一支小队全军覆没了
We lost another unit.
洛基 我们可以明天结束以后再...
Okay, Loki, I think we can finish up tomorrow and just pick it...
诡计多端的骗子
Mischievous scamp.
还真是意想不到呢
Wish I could say I was surprised.
-要是你没打断我们就好了  -我 错在我吗
- Yeah, I wish you hadn't interrupted us. - Me? It's my fault?
他跑不远的
Look, he can't have gotten very far.
分头行动 发现后立即裁剪
Split up. Prune on sight.
不要裁剪 不要重置 他还有用
No, no pruning, no resetting. He can still help us!
我记得你
Hey. I know you.
你是那个拿着蓝盒子的犯人
You're that criminal with the blue box.
你叫什么
What's your name?
凯西
Casey.
凯西 交出宇宙魔方 不然我把你当鱼剁了
Give me the Tesseract, or I'll gut you like a fish, Casey.
鱼是什么
What's a fish?
你怎么会不知道鱼是什么
How do you not know what a fish is?
我这辈子都在这张桌子后面
I've lived my entire life behind a desk.
那有什么区别吗
Well, what difference does it make?
我想知道你拿什么威胁我 再乖乖听话
I wanna know exactly what I'm being threatened with before I comply.
死亡 凯西 暴力痛苦的死亡
Death, Casey. Violent, painful death.
行了 行了 我听你的
Okay, okay. I comply, I comply.
我听你的 天呐
I comply. Jeez!
是这个吗
This it?
什么
What?
无限宝石
Infinity Stones?
怎么...
How...
怎么会有这些东西
How do you have these?
我们有好多呢
We actually get a lot of those.
有些人拿来当镇纸
Yeah. Some of the guys use them as paperweights.
有一些
Some of 'em.
这是宇宙最强的力量吗
Is this the greatest power in the universe?
你差点打到我了
Oh, you almost hit me!
太过分了
That's so messed up.
分头行动 检查楼下大厅
Split up. Check the lower concourse.
我不会原谅你的
I do not forgive you.
孩子们 我爱你们
I love you, my sons.
记住这个地方
Remember this place.
我们的家
Home.
洛基 你对我很重要
Loki, I thought the world of you.
我以为我们能并肩作战一辈子
I thought we were gonna fight side by side forever.
弟弟 也许你也没那么坏
Maybe you're not so bad after all, brother.
也许吧
Maybe not.
谢谢你
Thank you.
要是你真在这里 我都想抱抱你了
If you were here, I might even give you a hug.
我在这儿
I'm here.
不死的
Undying?
你真该好好斟酌你的用词
You should choose your words more carefully.
你...
You...
永远成不了...
will never be...
神
a god.
档案结束
有什么好笑的
What's so funny?
光荣的使命
Glorious purpose.
住...
Stop...
手
It.
住手
Stop it!
住... 住手... 住手...
St... Stop it... It... Stop it...
住... 手... 住手...
Stop... I... St... Sto... St...
这家伙还说要把我变成一条鱼
And this guy kept saying he was gonna turn me into a fish,
虽然不知道鱼是什么
whatever that is,
然后他们就来了 裁剪了我的手推车
and then they show up and just prune my cart,
所以我也做不了什么
so there was nothing I could have done.
你在这儿呢
Hey, there you are.
那个时间犯跑了
You know, that Variant you had got away.
洛基
Loki?
无处可逃了
Nowhere left to run.
我回不去了 对吧
I can't go back, can I?
回到我的时间线
Back to my timeline.
我并不喜欢伤害他人
I don't enjoy hurting people.
我...
I...
一点都不喜欢
I don't enjoy it.
只是因为我必须得做 别无选择
I do it because I have to, because I've had to.
解释解释
Okay, explain that to me.
那是幻象的一部分
Because it's part of the illusion.
是弱者残忍又精巧的手段 想让人害怕罢了
It's the cruel, elaborate trick conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
绝望地想要掌控全局
A desperate play for control.
你很了解自己
You do know yourself.
我是坏人
A villain.
我不这么想
That's not how I see it.
你想用那个吗
You try to use that?
试过几次
Oh, several times.
在这里 连无限宝石都没用
Even an Infinity Stone is useless here.
时变局真令人敬畏
The TVA is formidable.
我一直都这么觉得
That's been my experience.
我没法帮你实现救赎
Listen, I can't offer you salvation,
但我可以给你更好的
but maybe I can offer you something better.
有个在逃的时空犯一直在屠杀时间卫士
A fugitive Variant's been killing our Minutemen.
而你需要诡计之神来帮你阻止他
And you need the God of Mischief to help you stop him?
没错
That's right.
为什么选我
Why me?
我们找的这个时间犯
The Variant we're hunting is
就是你
you.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
俄克拉荷马州 萨莱纳
正在扫描...
分析
时间标记来自3000年早期
Time signature is early third millennium.
分析
肯定不符合时间线
Definitely anachronistic.
原油
Oil.
有混蛋利用时间机器
I think some jackass found himself a time machine,
穿越回来 想大发横财
came back here to get rich.
要分头找他吗 长官
Should we fan out and look for him, sir?
算了 不值得为这写份报告
Nah. It's not worth the paperwork.
直接裁剪 我们走 设好重置器
Just prune it. Let's bail. Set a charge.
等等 有人在那儿
Wait. Someone's out there.
检查一下
Check it out.
趴下
Get down!
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
感谢您到访时变局
Thanks for visiting the TVA.
欢迎您对我们的工作进行评价
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.